

sjt0689@gmail.com | H: 860-810-4716 | 281-C3 Maint St. , Farmington, CT 06032

Summary

Experienced Facility Technician with proven ability to work independently and maintain high levels of productivity. Commercial Facilities Technician with many years of maintenance experience in a Manufacturing Environment and additional industrial mechanical and electrical experience, including installation, wiring and troubleshooting of PLCs. Resourceful Facilities Tech with solid background in preventative maintenance repair.

Skills

- Blueprint reading and interpretation
- Troubleshooting
- Consistent work history
- Power tools
- Schematics reading
- Troubleshooting at component level
- Proficiency with mechanical and electric tools
- Computer literate
- Blueprint interpretation

- Production line/assembly line forklift experience
- Hydraulic activity skills
- Electrical system knowledge
- Electrical diagnostics
- Electrical maintenance
- Manual labor skills
- Conduit
- Pipe laying

Experience

Clark-Dietrich | Bristol, CT Mechanic II 09/2014 - 11/2018 Performed multiple functions in the areas of electrical, mechanical, HVAC, pneumatic and hydraulics.

- Conducted analysis to address countless issues which led to maintaining the high speed production of over 500,000 lbs of product per
- Delivered an exceptional level of service to each product line and all support systems.
- Performed root cause analysis of problems, documented faults in the tracking system and generated daily reports.
- Troubleshot, diagnosed and repaired rolling steel mill equipment.
- Provided hands-on technical support, advice and mentoring to all levels of personnel.
- Installed electrical equipment, facilities and systems for commercial puposes.
- Implemented advanced diagnostic tools to resolve customer complaints. Such as PLC troubleshooting, installation and repair.
- Accurately read blueprints and repair manuals to identify mechanical problems and fix them.
- Assisted in implementation of operations, maintenance and capital programs.
- Assisted in management of business operations by maintaining records and files, preparing cost and inventory reports, and ordering supplies.
- Reviewed work orders and communicated with prior shift to assess work needs for the day.
- Reduced downtime during production by maintaining equipment and

UTC Power | South Windsor, CT Electrician 08/2000 - 03/2013

reducing unnecessary maintenance.

- Cut, fit, and welded metal components, including plate, structural shapes, and pipe.
- Managed work with little supervision.

Performed multiple functions that supported the smooth, continuous and profitable procedures of high voltage equipment, switchboards, motors and controllers. All installation, repairs, troubleshooting, and maintenance work performed at high quality standards. Responsible for quickly and efficiently responding to maintenance requests.

- Traced and diagnosed malfunctions with hand tools and test equipment such as multi-meters.
- Worked on projects, which provided value to the department, the company, and the client base.
- Installed complicated circuit systems in commercial construction.
- Directed electricians on installation, maintenance and repair on electrical wiring and equipment.
- Troubleshooted electrical/electronic control circuits.
- Tested the entire electrical assembly for performance levels and safety concerns.
- Utilized a wide breadth of testing equipment to assess electrical systems, circuit continuity and accessory fixtures.
- Evaluated electrical systems, equipment and components to identify and resolve defects and safety risks.
- Consistently worked to code on all projects, utilizing drawings and manuals.
- Examined and created solutions for high voltage electrical system issues.
- Installed safety systems, including emergency lighting, uninterruptible power systems and battery systems.
- Operated equipment such as high-pressure boilers and large commercial air conditioning systems.
- Worked extensively on three-phase, 277/480 volt power distribution systems.
- Troubleshot, repaired and installed variable frequency drive systems.
- Responded to emergency callbacks and provided onsite support.
- Continued internal education, training and certifications to stay ahead of an evolving financial industry landscape, learned new product releases.
- Interpreted schematics, blueprints, and diagrams to complete projects on time.
- Tested and operated a variety of electrical components and systems.

Applied technical expertise to diagnosing, documenting, troubleshooting and repairing full scale turbine and motor/ generator power plant operations. Ensured that steam plant control systems and ships's battery ran at optimum levels without compromising safety by conducting efficient maintenance and repairs.

- Investigated and corrected problems with electrical and mechanical components.
- Oversaw the training and work of team members with a strong focus on outperforming expectations without sacrificing safety.
- Operated a wide range of useful tools to test and maintain equipment, including megometers and thermal imagers.
- Managed testing, inspection and maintenance of non-nuclear systems.

US Navy | Norfolk, VA Nuclear Electrician 10/1987 - 04/2000

- Logged and filed classified documents.
- Implemented vast knowledge of electronics principles to resolve complex electrical problems.
- Performed monthly, semi-annual and annual Preventive Maintenance Checks and Services (PMCS).
- Rebuilt and repaired printed circuit boards.
- Tested and repaired electric motors, variable frequency drives, alarms and control systems.
- Maintained electrical and mechanical components of gas and diesel engine-driven generators.

Education and Training

Jackson High School | Massillon, OH Electronics vocational 1987

US NAVAL NUCLEAR POWER PROGRAM | Orlando, FL NUCLEAR POWER 1988